LITTLE MISS U '99
[announcer in English]
Let's welcome Joanna Celis!
[singing in Filipino]
♪ Why do I love you so ♪
♪ Even though ♪
♪ You're in love with someone else? ♪
So you want to be an actress?
Yes, sir.
Do you know how to act?
- No, sir.
- ♪ Why do I love you so ♪
♪ Even though ♪
♪ You're in love with someone else? ♪
♪ Why am I so crazy about you... ♪
[Willie] Today's Little Miss U
with an average score
of 90 percent...
- Candidate number three...
- [Randy] Three.
- [Willie] ...Joanna Celis!
- [Randy] Joanna.
[engine revs]
[Chin] Hello, Sir Gab.
Please tell my family
that I love them all so much.
Please do that for me, Sir Gab.
[tense music]
What are you talking about?
I'm already in Taguig.
I won't be long now.
- Hail Mary, full of grace...
- [Gab] Chin.
Are you okay?
Will we make it?
Yeah, we'll make it. Chin?
[grunts]
I think this is the end for me.
You can do this, go on.
Come quickly, Sir Gab!
I'll be quick, I'm so close.
I can't do this. They'll kill me!
Just get to our meeting place.
- [Chin] Now?
- Yes, right now!
I'll try.
You sound like you're in a well.
- [Gab] Hey!
- [Mrs. Celis] Son of a gun!
- [Gab] Sorry!
- Gab!
- Sorry.
- [car horn honks]
[Gab] Move!
What's going on?
- [Mrs. Celis] What, is she sleeping?
- [Gab] Hey!
- [thuds]
- [exclaims]
- [Mrs. Celis] What's happening?
- Chin!
Chin?
[producer] Darn it, Chin!
Chin!
[tires screech]
[comical music]
- Excuse us. Coming through. Thanks!
- [man 1] What's that?
- [Gab] Mommy, watch out for the kid.
- [Mrs. Celis] Oh, my.
Hey there.
[crew] Shut the lights.
- [Gab] Where are they?
- [crew] She's not here yet.
- [Chin] Wait!
- [crew] Have your dinner break.
- [Chin] Sir Gab.
- [Gab] Coming through, please.
- Who's this?
- [Chin] It's me, Chin!
[Gab] Chin! Let's go! Hurry!
[Mrs. Celis] Oh, hey, Chin!
[Gab] Excuse me.
Careful, guys. It's really tight.
Careful now, Mommy!
[Chin exclaims]
[Chin] Darn it.
- Chin! Turn off the light.
- [Chin] Here you go.
- What happened anyway?
- [Mrs. Celis] Hurry up!
Did you go shopping in BGC?
The music video just wrapped up.
- [light switch clicks]
- Hey!
- [Gab] Shut the lights! Please!
- [crew] What...
- I'm so sorry.
- [Chin] Thank you.
The director is ready for Kiray.
We're coming, thank you!
[Chin] Didn't we pass on that gig?
You couldn't resist, Mommy?
- I didn't want to waste the gig!
- [light switch clicks]
- [in angry voice] Hey!
- Will you shut the lights?
- Oh, hello, ma'am.
- Hello.
She owns this house.
- [in calm voice] Oh, hello, Grandma.
- Hi, ma'am.
- Turn off the lights!
- Apologies.
Sorry. Thank you.
[Gab] Take care of this, Chin, okay?
[Chin] All right.
- Can you just shut the darn lights?
- [Mrs. Celis] Come on!
[producer] Okay.
[crew] Everyone standby! Ready!
[clatters]
- [Gab] Ms. Dindin!
- What the heck, Gab?
- Hello!
- It's been three hours!
We've been waiting for so long.
- I've run out of excuses!
- I know!
Right, and I'm here to explain...
- What happened was...
- Where's your road manager?
Where is that Chin-Chin?
- Chin.
- I've been looking for him!
That road manager is utterly useless!
Let me explain. Well, you see,
the other shoot went into overtime...
- I don't care!
- It rained and...
I don't care even if aliens
or whatever attacked you.
The meter is running here, Gabriel!
- I know, but...
- You know what?
This is the last time.
No, Ms. Dindin!
- I'm never hiring her again.
- No, please!
- And that freaking mother of hers...
- No!
...who'll hijack this ad
if we let her!
- I understand!
- [producer] This is too much!
- No, let me explain...
- [Kiray] Hello, everyone!
Hello! Hi!
- There she is.
- Kiray!
[producer] Hello!
- [Kiray] Hello!
- [producer] Kiray!
- Hello!
Finally, you are here.
Here's coffee.
- Have some coffee.
- That's nice.
- Okay, let's go.
- All right.
And Mommy Celis,
looking gorgeous as always!
[crew] Bubbles test, bubbles test!
[reporter] So what's next...
What's next for Kiray, Mommy C?
- You seem to be so busy!
- [Mrs. Celis] Yes.
Actually, we just finished
a music video.
- [reporter] And what else?
- [Mrs. Celis] And now this.
Right? So, Kiray's manager says
he has lots of projects
lined up for her.
You mean you're not Kiray's manager?
- [reporter] Uh, wait.
- [Mrs. Celis chuckles]
[Mrs. Celis] Not technically,
but I help them out.
- I'm like a co-manager.
- [phone ringing]
- [in English] Hey, Kelly!
- [Kelly] Hi, Gabriel.
Great news!
Everybody is raving
about Kiray's audition
for Women in Chains.
We saw lots of Filipino actors,
but kept coming back to Kiray.
She was that good!
And?
[Kelly] She got the part!
That's great news!
Thank you, thank you!
Perfect choice,
you won't regret this.
Thank you! Thank you, Kelly.
[Kelly] Oh, it's all Kiray.
Now, as soon as she gets
those surgeries
we can fly her out here
to meet the rest of the cast.
That's awesome.
She'll be very excited
to meet everyone.
Wait.
What surgeries?
We're still doing the surgeries?
Look, if you need me
to talk to the parents, I'll do it.
[Gab] But she's only 18 years old.
Eighteen?
You told me she was 21!
Yeah, that's what I meant, 21.
18, 21, she's an adult.
[Kelly] Look, they may still change
the title of the film.
I'm gonna send you the email
and the sizes we're looking at.
Sizes?
[clicking]
[Kelly] Look, Gabriel.
This is Quentin's favorite
Eddie Romero film.
He's been wanting to do
a Hollywood remake
of this movie for years
with a Filipino actor.
That could be Kiray!
But only if she has the surgeries!
This is gonna make her
an international artist!
The biggest decision of her life!
Kiray can hold her own
in the acting department.
She's going to be massive.
Biggest opportunity of her career.
It's an enormous chance!
Can we just get this done?
When this film is a huge success
you can rub it in everybody's faces.
Do you understand?
She's gonna take off after this.
But only if she has the surgeries!
[echoes] Surgeries...
It's a humongous opportunity!
You've got to grab it.
Grab it! Grab it! Grab it!
[director] Cut!
[theme music]
♪ Careful, careful ♪
♪ The world is full
Of jealous people ♪
♪ When envy strikes,
It means trouble♪
♪ That's why we need to be careful ♪
♪ Careful, careful ♪
♪ We always need to be careful ♪
♪ Prying eyes ready to snoop ♪
♪ Digging for the juiciest scoop ♪
♪ That's why we need to be careful ♪
♪ Careful, careful ♪
[train horn honks]
[thrilling music]
[indistinct chatter]
[Matthew] Noemi?
Noemi?
Noemi, where are you?
[in English] Shine Artist Management,
how can I help you?
[in Filipino]
Noemi, where is the contract?
And Director Richard's script?
Sir Matthew.
Let's go. Take everything with you.
[in English] I'm coming, sir.
I'll give you an update later today.
[Andrea]
Did you get any sleep at all?
- [Addy] Not really.
- [Andrea] Good.
We're visiting Nadine on set.
Right. 2:00 p.m.
Then we'll pick up Elisse.
- Yes, at 4:00 p.m.
- No!
- Switch them.
- Okay.
Nadine is doing a tracking shot.
- You're not thinking straight.
- Yes, Ms. Andrea.
[Addy] Oh, about Ms. Janine...
Ms. Andrea.
Do you think we'll be back
by 7:00 p.m.?
- Ms. Andrea?
- What?
Ms. Janine is asking for a meeting.
- Janine who?
- Gutierrez.
- Gutierrez?
- Yes, ma'am.
- What did you say?
- I said yes.
Oh, my god, why would you do that?
You have my schedule, right?
Are you out of your mind?
You know my schedule,
and you said yes?
- Take it back!
- She said it was urgent.
My schedule is so full!
[in English] Do something about it!
And I need my coffee!
I get it. Yes.
I understand.
Kelly, listen.
I don't want to lose this
for her either.
[in Filipino] Hi, I'm here to see...
[in English] Okay.
I'll send it over right away.
Okay, thank you.
Two minutes. Yes?
- Matthew Buenaventura, please.
- Sandra?
- Margie? Regal Films? Donna?
- [Deo] Cleaning!
Ms. Vivian?
Oro Holdings?
Thanks, Sofie!
It's Camille Vergara.
Camille Vergara.
A family friend.
Family friend.
Oh, my god, he's very busy.
[in Filipino] He can't meet anyone
without an appointment.
[in English] Shine Artist Management,
how may I help you?
[in Filipino]
You want to be an actress, right?
Just leave your resume and set cards.
I'm not an actress.
Miss, everybody wants to be a star.
- [Sofie] Okay, ma'am, yes...
- Is it okay to wait?
Yes, ma'am, bye!
Okay, here's what we'll do.
Give me an ID
and sign your name here.
I'll give you a visitor's pass.
[Sofie] We close at 9:00 p.m.
You can wait over there.
Mm...
Yeah, it's me, Niño Muhlach.
Okay, sir, I see.
I was Wonder Boy back in the day.
Child Wonder of Philippine Movies.
Maybe you've seen my film Kuwatog?
I played a dwarf.
Actually, that earned 6 million
in Metro Manila alone.
To think movie tickets
only cost 2.50 pesos back then.
Or maybe you've seen my film
with Lino Brocka?
Stop Crying, Little Boy?
Oh, maybe the one I did with Dolphy?
My Father, My Mother?
My manager was Mother Aleta.
She's a producer, right?
Now, she is.
But back in the day,
she was my manager.
Actually, I was her biggest star.
She's talking to SAM's owner now.
Because I'm going to make a comeback.
So, where did you recognize me from?
[hesitates]
Maybe my grandma would recognize you.
[Camille] Excuse me.
- Miss...
- [Sofie] Sofie.
Ms. Sofie, can you try Matthew again?
All right, wait, I'll check.
- Hello.
- [Sofie] Hi, Sir Matthew.
[in English] Um...
Camille Vergara here to see you.
Okay.
Okay, then.
Okay, bye.
[in Filipino] He's really busy.
Why do you want to speak to him?
- [Deo] Where do these go?
- Oh, my god!
Deo, that's a surprise!
[Sofie] We have to keep those hidden!
Matt!
I'm gonna grab a bite.
[in English] This is not happening.
You're not supposed to be here.
[in Filipino] Why are you here?
You want to be an actress
or something?
You're the second person
to ask me that.
Maybe I should be an actress.
Maybe I can work for you.
[in English] No! That's impossible.
That can never happen.
[exhales sharply]
In the meantime,
this will have to do.
[in Filipino] I don't want that.
[in English] You said you need work.
[in Filipino] I do!
[in English] I want to work.
Fine! If not for you,
for this agency.
[in Filipino]
I always check your social media.
I want to work here.
I want to earn my own money here.
Let's just talk on the phone.
[in English] We can't see each other.
[in Filipino] Especially not here.
I won't tell anyone.
[waitress in English]
Hi! Welcome to LibCafé.
[in Filipino]
Charge it to the office.
You said we're going to grab a bite.
[thrilling music]
[Addy] I can't do this.
This is too much.
It's gonna be fine. They're here.
Abi!
Come here.
Enough chit-chat.
Make sure the presentation is ready.
- Yes, Ms. Andrea.
- [Samuel] Oh!
Look who's here!
[Andrea] Mother!
- Hey, how are you?
- Good!
- I missed you!
- I missed you, too!
- Looking beautiful!
- Thank you!
No need to fuss.
I'm not staying long.
I'm only here to endorse Niño to you.
Can you send in Niño, please?
Which one is he?
[Aleta] Niño Muhlach.
Aga Muhlach's brother?
He was in Kuwatog.
My Father, My Mother.
[Matthew] And...
Stop Crying, Little Boy.
[in English] Exactly.
[Aleta in Filipino]
That's why I brought him here.
He needs to make a comeback.
Niño used to be
my biggest moneymaker.
- Now that he's old...
- Matt!
- ...he's all yours.
Buddy! Oh, here!
I brought you guys some ensaymada.
- Enjoy!
- Thank you!
Gabs!
- Bro!
- Long time, huh?
- Yup!
- How are you?
- Nice to see you.
Hello.
So, who's Niño's new manager?
Uh...
Um...
It should be someone
who can relate to me.
[Niño] Someone who's seen my films.
That's Matthew.
He's a big fan of yours.
- Matthew, take care of Niño, okay?
- Matt!
- Of course, Mother.
[in English]
I knew we were meant for each other!
[Aleta in Filipino]
When are you leaving for Germany?
- Let's talk.
- Uh...
- [Matthew] I'll text you.
- I fly tonight.
Are you taking Mrs. Mendiola or...
What's your new woman's name again?
Madel. Her name is Madel.
Hey.
- Mother!
- Hmm?
Are you jealous?
- [playful hooting]
- [laughs]
Let's go, Niño.
They're making fun of me.
- Bye, have a safe trip.
- [Samuel] Okay.
- [Aleta] Tata, we're leaving.
- Take care on the trip!
- [Samuel] Okay.
- [Niño] Bye!
[Matthew] Samuel.
[Samuel] I know, I know.
It's hard to get Niño roles.
But this is your job.
I hired you because you're good.
So be good at this!
- Okay. Time for updates!
- [Andrea] Updates!
[Matthew] I just closed...
endorsement deals
for Brandon and Jessica.
Two, as a matter of fact.
One is sports-related,
and the other is...
a lifestyle brand.
[Samuel] Well done!
[in English] But make sure
none of this gets in the way
of Juan Makabayan, okay?
I'm serious!
[in Filipino] This is huge!
Think about it.
A film shot
in the Philippines and Spain!
Have you read the script?
[in English] I did!
[in Filipino] It's great!
A great script! Really great.
[Matthew in English]
It's the rise and fall
of the great Filipino entrepreneur.
[in Filipino]
There's action and drama.
There's espionage and sex!
[in English] All in one movie.
- [in Filipino] This is epic!
- Yeah.
Imagine, it spans 50 years.
A ton of big scenes.
It's an acting piece!
There are good things ahead
for whoever plays Juan Makabayan.
I want our talents
to be in this project.
I want the lead actor
to be one of ours, okay?
[in English]
I'll take care of that, Samuel.
We should all be on top of that.
Because it's a big project.
[in Filipino]
We should all work to get this done.
I only offered because the producers
are my golfing buddies.
Oh, yeah?
I don't think golf
can get a film done.
Do you?
[in English] Huh? I don't think so.
[in Filipino] And Gab and I can help
scout locations in Spain.
Why? Because we have lots
of connections there.
[Andrea] The production
will appreciate us even more
if we use our connections.
Right, Gab?
Yes, of course! We can. Absolutely.
[in English] Guys, it's confirmed.
Eddie Romero's Women In Chains
is getting a Hollywood remake.
- Wow.
- And our very own
Kiray Celis got the lead part.
[in Filipino] Wow, that's good.
Ooh...
[in sarcastic tone] Hollywood, yay.
Whoo-hoo.
[in Filipino] You don't seem happy.
The deal is, Kiray has to get
breast augmentation surgery.
[scoffs]
Chin.
- [Samuel] Huh?
- Oh, wow.
[Samuel] Whoa, these are huge!
[Gab] I know.
I think I'm going to pass.
Gab.
Why would you pass up
an opportunity this big?
[Gab in English] She's only 18.
[in unison] Twenty-one.
Twenty-one.
Okay, 21.
I can't let her do this.
[in Filipino]
She doesn't even know what she wants.
She wants to be famous, right?
You mean they want to be famous.
Mrs. Celis will go crazy
over her earnings.
Good luck telling her
you want to give up that project.
I'm telling you.
Fine. I'll find her another one.
Other projects.
No, you need
to find her other projects.
Okay, other projects, then.
Chin is making content
for her social media pages.
We'll strengthen her online presence.
Gabriel, let me remind you
that SAM is in the business
of building stars
and not online sensations.
Well, actually...
So Kiray snagged the role!
Janine Gutierrez,
she also auditioned for that role.
But the production said
she was kind of mature for the role.
That's why it went to Kiray.
But it's still SAM.
[Samuel] What do they want,
a toddler?
[Andrea] I know, right? I don't know.
But, you know,
I have a ton of projects for Janine.
- And I can actually...
- [Addy whispering]
Is there something you want to share?
You have been at it the whole time.
[Andrea] You're distracting us.
Abi, is there something
you have to say?
[in English] Do you want
to share it with us?
[in Filipino] Nothing?
So can I continue?
[in English] Okay, thank you!
Okay. Going back.
I got two movies for Janine
a product endorsement,
and a possible series for her
and there's one more...
Abi, what else?
[in Filipino] I'm sure there's more.
There's nothing else.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
Not a thing.
No series, no movies. Nothing.
No endorsements. None. Zero.
Because she's moving
to another agency.
She doesn't want to be here anymore.
[nervous chuckle]
I'm so sorry.
I know nothing about this.
That's why Janine wanted
to meet with you.
You didn't want me to speak.
You wouldn't listen to me.
You won't let me speak.
You never listen.
You never let me speak.
You never let me speak!
You never ever let me speak!
[whimpers]
[shouting] Never! How crazy is that?
Are you screaming at me?
Yes, ma'am, I am screaming at you!
I can't take this job anymore!
No. I can't do this. I hate this!
I can't do this anymore!
No more of this, my god!
[in English] Oh, my god, Ms. Andrea!
I quit! I quit!
I... [pants]
Wait. I'll handle this.
Give me a second.
[Andrea in Filipino] Look, Abi,
it's just the way I talk.
You should be used to that by now.
We've been together for ages,
you're still this sensitive?
I've only been here
for two months, Ms. Andrea!
All the more reason to stay!
You have much more to learn from me!
There's so much more I can teach you!
And you graduated
Mass Communications, right?
I majored in Communication Research,
but there's nothing like that here!
[Addy shouts] Out of the way!
[Andrea] Abi!
I was 160lbs when I started here!
Look at how thin I've become!
Oh, my god, you have to be grateful.
You were 160lbs.
You look way better thin!
You should be thanking me.
- Abi, you can't leave...
- [Addy] Addy!
My name is Addy, not Abi!
- It's Addy!
- Abi suits you better!
My name is Adelaida del Monte!
You can't quit! My talents need you.
- They need you on their projects!
- [Addy] Just find someone else.
[Andrea] You can't go!
Who will take care of them?
You know their schedules!
You handle all their schedules!
If you resign from this office,
I'll make sure no one hires you.
I will make sure of that.
- [Addy] Okay!
- [Andrea] Once you leave this office
- no company will hire you!
- [Addy] Okay!
- I'll make your life a living hell!
- Okay, I get it!
Okay, go ahead!
[in English] You ungrateful girl!
[in Filipino] I feel better now!
Fuck!
[exhales sharply]
Okay, please get me an appointment
with Janine Gutierrez.
Anytime she's available today,
I'm okay.
Why me? What happened with Addy?
She resigned, remember?
[Andrea] Find me
another road manager.
Ms. Andrea, that's your fourth one.
I don't know anyone else to hire.
Excuse me.
[Sofie] Didn't I already
give your ID back?
Me. You can hire me.
I'm sorry, who are you?
Camille.
[Sofie] Are you sure, miss?
First job?
I interned at Cinemalaya.
I studied Mass Communication.
Are you a sleepyhead?
Not really.
Good. I handle 16 celebrities.
Eight of them are big stars.
Three of them are medium,
two rising, three character actors.
You'll be their road manager.
Road manager?
Road manager, yes.
Meaning, you'll be with them on set
because you know their schedules.
You have to make sure
they'll come on set on time
and that they've memorized
all their lines.
If someone messes with your talents,
you mess with them.
You take the blows and the bruises.
Never the talent.
You see that coffee shop over there?
That one, see that?
You'll get my coffee there
every morning.
[in English] My coffee
is an organic decaf soy latte.
Please remember that.
[in Filipino]
If your shooting location
is anywhere near here
you'll get your talent's orders
there too.
Everything they want, get it there.
You make sure their taxes
are filled out and paid.
- Got it.
- If a fan wants a picture
you take the camera, the phone,
or whatever gadget it is.
Make sure the talent is clearly seen,
and it's the correct angle.
It's fine if the fans' faces
are blurry.
Okay.
If the talent farts, take the blame.
You go to the producer
and collect their fees.
Manicures and pedicures
are very important.
The talent's nails
should always be clean.
Dirty nails are bad for their image.
A foot spa is a must.
If they also need hair and makeup,
then go and do it, I don't care.
In short, you represent me
and Shine Artist Management.
Can you do it?
- Can you?
- I can.
Am I hired?
You're a Mass Communication
graduate, right?
- What's your major?
- [Camille] Film.
Gab, I'm an old man.
[Samuel] You're making me dizzy.
Sorry, boss.
I just don't know what to do.
[Gab] Matthew's right, it's one movie
but she'll be a star overnight.
She could be set for life with this.
But...
Am I the only one who feels sorry?
[in English]
It seems like everything's happening
so fast for her, and...
Seriously?
Breast augmentation?
[in Filipino] I trust you'll make
the right choice, Gab.
That's it?
No words of wisdom?
- No advice?
- Huh?
Gab, will you sit down?
Relax! Sit.
What advice can I give someone
who is almost just like me?
You know everything I know.
There's nothing left to teach you.
The one thing I can't teach you
is the gut feel.
Everything you need
is in that brain of yours.
Whatever your heart tells you,
you have to figure that out.
I taught you everything,
how to play the game.
The rest is up to you.
Shit!
[Samuel] Do you see it clearly now?
I have to go. See you later!
[somber music]
Excuse me.
[background chatter]
[background chatter continues]
[Gab] Lora!
Lora? I'm not Lora!
Sorry!
Hello!
[Lora over phone] I'm driving.
Uh... I'm here.
[Lora] Your son and I already left.
Can I talk to Joey?
[Lora] He's napping. I need to go.
The cops will see me on the phone.
- Wait! Can't you wake him up for me?
- [dial tone beeps]
Hello?
[upbeat music]
[Chin] Administrative departments
are on this floor.
HR, Accounting, Library, Procurement.
Okay, and here's the lobby.
Come on, quickly!
There's the one
who refused to let you in.
- You've met Sofie, of course?
- [Sofie] Yes.
This is our photocopy area.
'Cause, you know,
photocopying is life.
This is our main conference room,
where we do all our meetings.
- Even me?
- Of course!
Road managers attend meetings.
- [hammer thudding]
- You were here earlier, right?
This is where you had your interview.
[Chin] Wait.
This is Deo, our maintenance man.
Deo!
Please check the lamp
in Sir Gab's room.
It keeps winking at me
like it wants me.
Have a look at it, okay?
Thank you!
[in English] And this.
This is the heart
of Shine Artist Management.
[in Filipino] Here is
the most exciting department at SAM.
You've met Andrea, of course.
You're her road manager. Good luck.
That's Gabriel, my boss.
He's a bit preoccupied these days.
He just separated from his wife.
You'll meet Matthew soon,
he's just busy.
He's a senior manager too.
That one is Noemi, his road manager.
[Chin in English]
I saved the best for last.
Oh!
Welcome to the pantry!
[Daisy] Were you able to heat that?
[in Filipino] Let's wait here
for other people you haven't met.
[Chin] Keep this pantry
close to your heart.
Starting tomorrow
you'll have breakfast here, lunch,
snacks, dinner, even midnight snacks.
That is, if you're not on set.
Hey, don't forget
the fish you ordered.
Is that still fresh, Miss Daisy?
Fresher than you, girl!
And here you are, trespassing again.
You don't even work here!
Anyway, here's your tablet.
Everything's already there,
your username and password.
All the artists and celebrities
under Shine Artist Management
are listed there
as well as
their senior managers, okay?
Names, contact info, addresses,
contact sheets. It's all there.
Explore and study it, okay, Camille?
Any questions?
- Not really.
- Okay.
Thank you, Chin!
See you tomorrow!
You mean I can go home now?
Sis?
Enjoy it
while the answer's still "yes".
When you get home,
call everyone dear to you
because starting tomorrow
your days will be longer.
You'll live here now.
[in English]
Welcome to Shine Artist Management!
[telephone rings]
Hello.
Where?
Hello?
[thuds]
Sofie?
[in Filipino] Where is everyone?
[cell phone vibrating]
[gasps]
What do I tell Sir Samuel?
Didn't you tell him where to go?
- No.
- You idiot!
- Hey!
- [Sofie] My phone!
[Sofie gasps]
[cell phone vibrating continues]
[Gab] Quickly!
[Andrea] Give her phone back.
[Gab] Here you go.
- He's here...
- [gasps]
What's all this?
[in unison] Surprise!
[calm music]
We can't let you leave
without a send-off, Samuel!
- Of course.
- A send-off?
I'll only be gone for two weeks!
To make you look even more handsome.
- Wow!
- Thank you!
Looks good!
- Looks good!
- Looks good. Thank you, Noemi.
- This is for you.
- Thank you, everyone.
[cheering]
[sighs]
You know... [clears throat]
...people always say
I'm the heart of SAM.
[Samuel] But that's not true.
Part of my job is to teach you
everything I know
about this industry.
My biggest source of pride
is that I picked
the right people to teach.
You're the heart
of Shine Artist Management.
[in Filipino] Don't ever forget that.
- [Gab] Yes, boss.
- Okay.
- Cheers!
There's more to say
but I'll save the rest
for my retirement.
[all laugh]
Just keep on working
on those projects
especially Juan Makabayan!
- [Andrea] Juan Makabayan.
- Okay.
[Samuel] And no fighting
while I'm away, okay?
[overlapping dialogue]
See you in two weeks. Okay.
- See you!
- Cheers!
[camera shutter clicks]
[overlapping dialogue]
[employee] Love you, boss! Love you!
[comical music]
Sir, I need one last signature.
- You barely made it!
- Please, sir?
Maybe you should sign it?
Only you can do it, sir.
There you go.
- Okay.
- Thank you, sir, love you!
Samuel, I...
I just want to apologize for earlier.
[in English]
It's totally uncalled for.
I'm so sorry.
[in Filipino]
Look, I get how passionate you are.
But you put too much pressure
on yourself
that you take it out on others.
Take a breath. Okay?
[in English] Relax.
Yeah, I'll take note of that.
Take care of yourself, okay?
- You too.
- Okay.
- Have fun.
- [in Filipino] And you, Gab.
- Remember everything I said.
- Okay.
Samuel.
[in English]
Don't worry about Juan Makabayan.
[in Filipino] I'll handle it.
[in English] We've come far, Matthew.
[in Filipino] SAM would not be SAM
if I didn't convince you to join me.
[in English] Thank you.
[in Filipino] I want you to know that
it's you that I trust the most.
Um...
Don't make any decisions
until I get back.
Um...
[in English] What do you mean?
[in Filipino]
We'll talk when I get back.
Take care.
You too.
[in English] Have fun!
- We'll miss you, boss!
- [in Filipino] Take care!
[dramatic music]
Hello. Good evening.
- [roommate 1] Did you eat already?
- [roommate 2] Have some dinner.
[Camille] I'll go unpack first.
Thank you.
- Hello.
- Hi.
That's your bed.
Okay. Thank you.
[cell phone vibrating]
Hello, Mom.
[in English] Guess what?
[in Filipino] Margie, I can't fight
that soap opera about schedules!
They said it's down
to the last two episodes.
Don't believe them. Check again.
Cel? Pull up the file for the budget.
Yes, Mother, hang on.
Rey, my piano is still out of tune!
I just finished tuning it, Mother.
Mother, here is the maquette.
Okay, it's nice.
- [yelps]
- How about this, Mother?
Let me hear it.
- [piano plays]
- There you go.
[exclaims] Too high!
The budget?
Not you, Cel. I mean Rey.
[Aleta] It's too high!
How much?
We agreed on 20,000.
[prop maker]
This is 25,000, 15,000, and 5,000.
Twenty thousand? That's too high!
Mother, here it is.
The finest toilet bowl we have.
- I don't like the color.
- [gasps]
Do it again. Try it again.
[piano plays high key]
It's still too high.
Change it.
We won't even see that on screen.
This is a night scene, right?
Let's go with the 5,000.
- [prop maker] And this?
- [Aleta] Very good.
But I get a discount.
It's only one eye.
Mother, you were right.
They still have two weeks left
on that soap opera.
I told you so. Replace it!
The entire piano?
Not you, Rey!
Margie, give me the list
of everyone you will replace.
That's all good.
The tune?
No, Rey. No.
Cel, for the budget
- it's all good to me.
- Yes, ma'am.
Rey! Do not leave
until that piano is tuned, okay?
Okay.
Okay. Bye.
[exhales sharply]
[comical music]
[server] Here you go, Mother.
I spend a lot of money here every day
so this dessert should be free, okay?
- Yes, Mother.
- Okay.
And you, mister?
[Niño] Mother.
All they give me are father roles.
I'm too young for that.
So what do you want?
Do you wanna be in a love team?
A rom-com?
I'm serious, Mother.
Niño.
Stop asking me for all these things.
I already gave you stardom.
Your comeback is in SAM's hands now.
Mother, is that guy from SAM too?
[inaudible dialogue]
That's Paul Amir.
He's not from SAM.
He's from Galaxy Entertainment.
Hi!
[in English] How are you?
[tense music]
[Sofie] Thank you!
[Andrea in Filipino] Sofie, a favor?
- [thuds]
- Sofie!
Ms. Andrea, please watch my play.
- [Sofie] Take Sir Gab with you.
- Sure.
- [Andrea] Sure.
- Okay then, Ms. Andrea.
- Okay?
- What can I do for you?
Okay, good.
[in English] Please send Cassie
a beautiful bouquet of flowers.
[in Filipino] And an order
of her favorite nachos.
Then add a very cute and lovely note.
Something like, "I love you forever."
Or if you think of something better.
You kids would know what to say.
Uh...
Yes?
Which Cassie, Ms. Andrea?
Cassie, my girlfriend. Who else?
The new girl can't do this.
She hasn't even met Cassie.
[in English]
So please, can you do it for me?
[in Filipino] Seriously?
Here.
WHY, WHAT HAPPENED?
[cell phone vibrating]
[exhales sharply]
[scoffs]
[Cassie over phone] Andrea.
Babe!
[Cassie in English]
Stop calling me that.
Wait! [scoffs]
[in Filipino] What did I do?
Why are you so angry?
[Cassie] We're done talking.
I've been telling you for weeks.
I want out.
[Andrea] Is this about my workload?
[in Filipino] I can cut back on work.
[in English]
You know what, I could give...
Some of my talents
to Gab, to Matty, and...
So we can spend more time together!
[in Filipino]
That's what you want, right?
No!
My god, you're not listening again.
[in English] Amazing!
[Andrea] Wait, babe. Please.
[in Filipino] Stop being angry.
[in English]
Just tell me what you want.
[in Filipino] What I want
- is for you to get a life, Andrea.
- [video call wavering]
- You're suf...
- Shit! The signal.
[video call wavering]
- I know this is harsh, but...
- [yells] Signal!
What? Why do you say I smother you?
[in English]
I give everything you want, Cassie.
What are you talking about?
[Cassie in Filipino] That's just it.
You like everything I like.
[in English]
My hobbies, the food that I eat.
Even my hair!
It's like you're trying to be me.
- [car horn honks]
- Wait!
[in Filipino] Not you... I mean...
Fine, go ahead!
I thought that would make you happy.
[Cassie] You're allergic to garlic,
but you eat it because I love garlic.
You hate jazz,
but you go to concerts with me.
You couldn't care less about Lego,
but now you're a collector.
Isn't it good
that I make adjustments for you?
Definitely not!
Ms. Andrea! You're not allowed there.
I'm not allowed here.
[mouths] Wait.
Fine, I'm leaving.
I hate my life.
[in English] Cassie, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
[in Filipino] Your entire world
can't revolve around me, Andrea.
It's not healthy for you or for me.
[in English] I just love you so much.
I just love you so much. [sobs]
[Cassie in Filipino]
I know I'm the only one you love.
But I can't be the only one you like.
I'm not a bad person, Andrea.
I would never ask my girlfriend
to make those sacrifices.
I don't need it.
[in English]
I don't know who you are anymore.
[in Filipino] You're so fake.
[in English] Look, I promise.
I promise I can change.
Good.
[in Filipino] Do that for your sake.
But you'll have to do it alone
because I'm done.
[in English] Goodbye, Andrea.
[sobbing]
[sobbing continues]
[in Filipino] Stupid Cassie.
It's just Cassie.
[sobbing]
[sobbing continues]
[breathes deeply]
There's plenty
of other women out there.
With legs longer than hers.
[quivers]
[exhales sharply]
[exhales]
[in English] I hate you, Cassie.
Okay.
[door closes]
[toilet flushes]
Uh...
[in English]
Let's start this meeting!
[in Filipino] Where's my RM
and what's her name?
It's Camille.
- And where's Camille?
- Right here.
Get me a meeting with Janine now.
Isn't it too early for a meltdown?
Sir Gab, this is Camille.
Ms. Andrea's new RM.
- Hi, Camille.
- Hello, sir.
Do you guys have
Janine Gutierrez's number?
[all in unison] Tablet.
Go ahead. Test it.
Test it... No, wait.
There, I see blood. That's enough.
[Aleta] I'm buying the blood.
Okay, we're done.
Don't forget the cost breakdown.
- [seller] Okay, ma'am.
- [Matthew] Mother.
Another meeting?
- Matthew!
- Mm-hm.
Thanks.
How about you?
Another meeting?
What, you mean last time?
No, that wasn't a meeting.
Paul and I are old golfing buddies.
We were just catching up.
Mmm...
Even when I was just a manager in SAM
I've always held my meetings here.
So I've heard.
It's almost like you own the place.
[Aleta chuckles] Agree.
[in English] This is the place
where deals are made
and dreams are broken.
[in Filipino]
This was where I told Samuel
that I was leaving SAM
to become a producer.
Really? Samuel never told me that.
I can't admit it
but I really do favor SAM.
I spent some of my best years there.
I saw Samuel's hard work
to make a star out of SAM.
If something bad ever happens to SAM
like Samuel, it would hurt me too.
Kiray.
So you've heard the good news.
[Gab] Congratulations, they love you!
They want a Filipino actor for
Women in Chains, and they want you.
I had to learn
from a casting agent friend
that I didn't get the part.
You know what,
I just found out myself
that Kiray got it.
But still, honey, it's not
a good reason for you to leave SAM.
Thanks God!
But Kiray needs
breast augmentation surgery.
What?
Wait. Is that in the contract?
Not yet, but they'll add it in.
She'll have to get the surgery.
And if we refuse?
They loved your audition!
It was beautiful.
I saw it and I agree.
[Andrea] You were so good.
But no one told me
why I didn't get it.
Hello, Pappy? Get here right away!
They'll blow up our baby's boobs!
[in English] It's just that,
according to them
you were a bit on the mature side.
Mature?
[Janine] Seriously?
[in Filipino] "Mature" as in "old"?
Maybe they'll still grow some more.
I'm only 18 years old.
- Twenty-one.
[in English] Andrea, I'm only 26!
Twenty-six?
You look 20 to me.
[in Filipino] Gabriel, we agreed
to change her showbiz age to 21
to get her bigger and better roles.
Now she needs showbiz boobs too?
But the role
requires you to be
a bit more mature and hot.
So what's the problem, then?
Asking price?
Hot? How about this?
Why didn't you fight for me?
Janine, of course I did!
I would never abandon my talents!
[in English] And, sweetheart,
I love you so much!
You know I'll do everything for you!
[in Filipino] But...
You wouldn't lower your rate
so that's two points against us.
[Andrea] You shouldn't have done
those mother roles.
[in English] Oh, my god.
Andrea, this is unbelievable!
[in Filipino]
I'm almost the same age as Kiray!
[Janine] And for the record,
she looks older than me!
She looks like my older sister!
[Gab] That's what I told
the casting agent.
Maybe you can use a costume instead?
And I'm scared
of any kind of surgery.
Okay!
So we're passing on the project.
We can find more projects
for you here.
And even internationally.
We can make paid social media content
for advertising.
I'll make you a social media star!
We'll get
that 150,000-dollar talent fee
somewhere else!
One hundred and fifty thousand...
US dollars?
Exactly!
So you're saying the older I get,
the less expensive I should be?
[in English]
For that role and for that project?
Multiplied by 60.
Hello, Pappy?
[in Filipino] You don't need to come.
We'll talk later.
And tell Didi she can now go
to school in France.
Her sister is making a new movie!
Ask me where!
In Holy Wood! [squeals]
[in English] But look, Janine.
- Oh, my god.
- [Andrea] There are more better
and bigger roles for you.
You're a very talented star.
You're beautiful. You're young.
[in Filipino]
There's so much we can do together!
You and I, I promise you that!
They are kind of tiny.
[Mrs. Celis]
It's for your career, baby!
Let's look at it this way.
Your future will be brighter
if your boobs are bigger.
If you can't do your job
then I'll go to an agency
that can do the job for me.
[retreating footsteps]
Hi!
[Kiray] Hey, Janine!
How are you?
[in English] I'll be okay. Soon!
So fresh! See you around!
[sighs]
Before anything else
if anyone comes in,
what's the safe word?
- "Volleyball."
Very good, children!
Okay, what else?
That's it.
After she was dumped, the call ended
and she just sobbed.
[Chin] Poor Ms. Andrea.
Serves her right
for being such a jerk.
Hey, she's going through a lot.
I've worked here the longest.
I know that she's kind...
Volleyball!
[clears throat]
- [Noemi] She's a kind player!
- [Chin] Right.
- I always watch her play.
- [Sofie] Me too.
- A "kind" player?
- Yes, kind.
How can a player play kindly?
- She's kind to her opponents.
- [Sofie] We all agree.
We just have to accept the fact that
she can be a mean player sometimes.
[gasps]
[Daisy] Yeah, that's how it is.
That player, I mean.
- Do you agree?
- [Sofie] Yes.
You have time for gossip, huh?
Be quick, we have lots of work to do.
- [Chin] Yes, ma'am.
- [Sofie] Yes, ma'am.
- [Noemi] Yes, ma'am.
- [Camille] Yes, ma'am.
All clear, she's gone.
Here's more.
You know Ms. Andrea.
She's a film major.
She's intense and driven.
That's just how she is.
[Sofie] With work
and her love life too.
So heartbreaks are also so intense.
[Chin] Too bad.
You know,
I still haven't met Sir Matthew.
- Is he a good boss?
- [Daisy exclaims]
Of course! Good and good-looking!
- Sir Matthew is so macho!
- [Sofie] Sir Matthew is so macho!
[Noemi] Are you making fun
of Sir Matthew?
Noemi wouldn't last here
if Sir Matt wasn't a good boss.
For me, he's the best.
He manages
the biggest talents in SAM.
[Noemi] That's how good he is.
[Daisy] Look how proud she is!
[Chin] Very proud.
Right. He's not a film major
but it seems he knows
what's best for his talents.
He's a business graduate.
How did you know
he wasn't a film major?
[Sofie] Wait a minute.
I've been wondering about something.
You say you don't know Sir Matthew.
But when you first got here
you asked specifically
for Sir Matthew.
I read it on the website!
The website!
[Camille] I wanted to work here.
I saw his name on the website.
[playful music]
Can you just stick to Ms. Andrea?
- [Chin exclaims]
- Because Sir Matthew is mine.
- Oh! Yours? Like you own him?
- [Chin gasps]
[Noemi] It's not like that!
[laughs]
Did she change her name to "Hope"?
Just give up on Sir Matthew.
How about Sir Gab? He's single now.
- Ms. Andrea too.
- [Chin] I'll set you up.
You think that will work?
Seriously, I really don't know
how to help Ms. Andrea.
[line ringing]
Come on, Cassie! Pick up!
Where are you?
[Gab] Just give Cassie
the space she wants.
She's right.
You do smother her sometimes.
[Andrea] Excuse me.
I know how to compromise.
But how can I show her that
if she won't even speak to me?
She won't even take my calls.
And do you mind
not taking her side today?
It's all too fresh.
[sighs]
[in English] I just miss her so much.
[in Filipino] I miss Joey too.
[somber music]
Camille.
[in English]
I told you not to come back here.
[in Filipino] Wait.
I can give you a monthly allowance.
Just give me your bank details.
No one knows
I have a daughter out of wedlock.
This will ruin me.
[Andrea] Oh, you're here!
[in English]
Anyway, I need you to do something.
Leave this in my office, okay? And...
[in Filipino]
Do you two know each other?
- Not at all.
- Oh, not yet.
Matthew Buenaventura,
our senior manager.
- This is Francine...
- Camille Vergara.
Camille Francine Vergara.
My new road manager.
Come on.
[in English]
Sure. 2:00 p.m. on Tuesday.
Hold on.
[Noemi] Okay, I'll sign that later
in the afternoon.
Thank you. Yes.
I'll have to check.
- Noemi.
- Sorry, hold on.
- Yes, sir?
[in Filipino] Is my three o'clock
in Makati or Quezon City?
Quezon City.
[Niño] Matthew!
Oh, Niño.
Have you been here long?
I brought some scripts.
Let's read them together.
There might be something here for me.
But I'm so busy... So busy.
[Niño] These are from Mother Aleta.
How about this one?
A drama!
Light drama.
[Matthew] You're a widower.
Lame, deaf, and mute.
Five children.
This is a lead role, Niño. A lead!
- The very lead.
- Yeah.
Okay. Maybe this one.
A thriller.
You play a killer.
With a beard and long hair.
Something like an anti-hero.
And you're not just any killer.
- You're a serial killer.
- There it is.
That doesn't suit me!
How about this one?
Perfect! Horror sells right now.
You are a "goblin of the anthill".
Just like Lord of the Rings!
No.
The Hobbit.
I hate that!
Isn't there something like...
Like what Aga shot in Dubai?
Or Alden in Hong Kong?
Or Joshua Garcia in Tanay?
A heartthrob role like Piolo.
Nothing like that.
What about this?
Juan Makabayan.
Maybe there's something here for me?
- Noemi.
- Yes, Sir Matthew?
Where's my 3:00 p.m. meeting,
in QC or Makati?
- In QC.
- [Matthew] Ah, QC.
And I have a four o'clock?
[Noemi] 80 kilometers away
in Bulacan.
Then five o'clock...
Hi, Kiray, welcome to my clinic!
Thank you so much.
- Are you excited?
- [Kiray] Yes, very!
We're so glad you're here, finally!
Hi!
Hello!
Thank you, Doc!
- [Dr. Aivee] Are you excited?
- Yes!
Kiray will be the new face
of my clinic!
Isn't that right?
According to the Hollywood producers
aside from
breast augmentation, Kiray...
We should get your skin lightened
and if you can, get your nose done
and anything else we can fix.
Am I really that ugly?
Kiray, think of it as enhancement.
We'll make you even more beautiful.
That's not so bad, baby!
[Dr. Z in English]
Kiray, don't worry.
These are the best implants
that money can buy.
It feels natural.
- [Dr. Aivee] Have a look.
- [Dr. Z] You can have a feel of it.
[in English]
It's almost like the real thing.
[in Filipino] Baby, try this.
Can I see that?
Or try this one.
[Dr. Aivee] Kiray, while we're at it,
and you're asleep anyway
we can do your face too.
The eyes, the nose, the jawline.
And we can reduce the double chin.
The trend nowadays
is to have a face as small as a CD.
Just like this.
Uh... [nervous chuckle]
Is it okay if I talk to Kiray alone?
We'll come back later.
- [Dr. Z] Yeah.
- [Dr. Aivee] Of course.
- Yeah, take your time.
- Let's go.
Excuse us.
Kiray, hey!
[sobs]
I knew it.
We're passing on this project.
Look, you're young
and you're very talented!
You don't need this.
- What about the 150,000 dollars?
- [shushes]
[whispers] What about...
What about the 150,000 dollars?
This is Hollywood!
We have a shot at winning an Oscar!
Think about it!
Please, honey. Please?
We'll find something else.
There's a lot more.
We don't need Hollywood.
Okay?
Kiray, you deserve better.
[wails]
[shushes]
[in English]
It's for the best, Kelly.
There's really nothing more to say.
[Gab] So, as her manager
I'm officially informing you
that Kiray Celis
is passing on Women in Chains.
Well, that's
very disappointing, Gabriel.
[Gab] I know and I'm sorry.
But, hey, isn't Janine Gutierrez
up for the role?
Maybe you can see her again.
Too old. Too expensive.
[Kelly] Look.
This is not a low-budget indie movie.
This is from a Hollywood studio
packed with A-listers.
Money coming out of everybody's ears!
You're ruining her career.
This is a big mistake.
[scoffs, chuckles]
Sorry, I don't think so.
I'm just doing
what's best for my artist.
Artist?
She can't get past a simple boob job,
how can she call herself an actor?
Excuse me?
[Gab] Excuse me,
actors are people too, Kelly.
And this particular person not only
has the acting chops of actors
thrice her age and experience
she's also sweet, kind, innocent,
and sensitive.
She has a bright future ahead of her
even without the boob job. Okay?
So I'll never force her
to do something
that she will possibly regret
for the rest of her life
just so she could star
in your major Hollywood film.
[exhales sharply]
But...
Please don't get mad at her. Uh...
We both made that decision,
so that's it.
- [Gab] Sorry.
- Well, you've both made a mistake.
[Kelly] Look, Gabriel,
it's not too late.
There are still script revisions.
They're changing the title.
Think about it, give me a call.
I don't think so. Uh...
Thank you. Bye, Kelly.
[in Filipino] How was that?
Nailed it.
[both chuckle]
[thrilling music]
We need more projects for Kiray.
- How many?
- [Gab] A shitload, Chin!
- I'm counting on you.
- [Chin] I got this.
[action music]
THIS YEAR
THE MOST ANTICIPATED
ALIAS: COUNTRYSIDE KID
THE NEW CHAPTER
[gun fires]
THE COUNTRYMEN
[overlapping dialogue]
[Malou] Yes, she's so good.
- Kiray Celis is brilliant.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Right?
- I like the kid.
Would you have any projects...
[shouts] Projects!
[Chin] Projects for her.
I need you
to get something for Janine.
Something vintage.
[Andrea] She likes stuff like that.
Make sure it's cute.
Vintage, not old-fashioned.
- [Camille] Yes, ma'am.
- Have it gift-wrapped and delivered.
- Today. It has to be today.
- Okay.
I'll handle it.
You keep asking me to sign.
Where's your liquidation, dumbass?
- [Hermie] You know, girl...
- [Chin] Yes, ma'am?
Your talent is really good.
- Superb acting.
- Yes.
But I'm reminding you.
- What is it?
- Don't let it get to her head
and make her a production headache.
That won't be a problem with her.
[Roselle] Oh, yes!
I know Kiray Celis.
Yes, she's so good.
Even in Little Miss U
I knew she was gonna get far.
[thrilling music]
[seller] Everything in here
is antique.
- [explodes]
- [screams]
Hey! This is a low-budget.
Enough with the explosions!
[both laugh]
You know how it is in showbiz.
[in English]
"What you see is what they will get."
- Okay.
- [in Filipino] What I recommend...
She needs bigger breasts.
- Bigger breasts?
- But not too big.
Bigger boobs.
But not as big as coconuts.
Gross.
Maybe you can consider a boob job?
- Something just right.
- [screams]
- Right! Just right!
- Dust mite?
Arci?
Oh, wow!
- What's up?
- Sister!
I didn't recognize you! You look...
- Did you get something done?
- Oh, come on!
[thrilling music]
How much for this one?
It's so pretty.
But it's so expensive.
I hope Ms. Janine likes it.
I hope she doesn't leave Shine.
Uh, Noemi,
the other scripts on my desk.
I need copies of those.
[in English]
All right, will do, Sir Matthew.
Sir Matthew, by the way, this is...
[in Filipino] We've met.
I see. Okay.
Camille.
[Matthew] I can get you another job.
I know people.
You can be a production manager.
Or even an assistant director.
[in English]
You just can't work here.
But I like it here.
[in Filipino]
I won't tell anybody you're my dad.
Nobody will find out.
[in English]
We don't have to work together.
[in Filipino]
I work for Ms. Andrea anyway.
Andrea is a difficult boss.
She's very demanding.
It'll be tough for you.
[in English] Why do you care?
[clears throat] Camille!
[in Filipino]
Ms. Andrea's looking for you.
[in English] Excuse me.
Yes, Ms. Andrea?
[in Filipino]
Did Janine get her gift?
Yes.
Call her. Speakerphone.
[cell phone ringing]
- [in English] Yes?
- [Andrea] Hi, Janine!
Did you get it? Did you like it?
Why would you give me a hand mirror?
[Janine in Filipino]
To remind me that I'm too old
for the biggest role of my career?
[in English] But that's vintage!
[Janine scoffs] Apparently, so am I.
- [exhales sharply]
- Look. I appreciate it. Okay?
[in Filipino] Maybe...
I'm just sensitive right now.
But you really should be too.
Anyway, it's a good thing you called
because I wanted to tell you
I'm thinking of signing
with Paul Amir of Galaxy.
[in English]
So I guess this is goodbye.
Thanks, Andrea.
You're fired.
Get out of my office.
Get out!
- [in Filipino] Are you okay?
- I'm okay.
- What happened?
[indistinct chatter]
[sighs]
[in English] Look.
Okay, you're not fired.
Ms. Andrea, I'm sorry.
[in Filipino]
I know things can get tough here.
Especially since it's your first day.
So stop crying.
It's gonna get worse.
So don't waste your tears on this.
What's the problem?
[in English] Well...
Janine suddenly decided
that she's finally out of SAM.
[in Filipino]
So, SAM just lost Janine Gutierrez.
Well, then let's look
for another Janine.
Come on, I'll buy you a drink.
Let's drown your worries in alcohol.
Me? I'm celebrating.
What's there to celebrate?
I feel relieved.
I've decided to pass on
Women In Chains for Kiray.
What?
Oh, my god,
you should have decided sooner!
You know, because maybe if you did
I could have gotten Janine that part
and maybe she would still be in SAM.
Excuse me.
Are you out of your minds?
[in English]
Do you realize how much money
we could have made from that film?
Samuel said it was up to me.
[in Filipino]
And that's what I decided.
I can live with losing that project
than have my talent
go through that surgery.
Besides, I already told Kelly.
End of conversation.
- Let's go, Andrea.
- Let's go. I agree.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, Ms. Manuel.
Can you explain
why you let Janine leave SAM?
You let her leave, now it's possible
she'll head to our biggest rival.
[in English]
I don't have to explain to you.
What?
[in Filipino] Do you realize
what you've done to SAM?
It's not like
we're not doing our jobs.
You call that "doing your jobs"?
[Matthew] You passed on
what could have been
the biggest break
of your talent's career.
Can you please just let it go, okay?
The project's gone.
Janine left already.
- Just... Just get off of our backs!
- [telephone rings]
Why don't you just focus
all your energy on Niño Muhlach?
You seem to be a good match.
Focus on finding projects for him!
Stay away from us!
Maybe he can go audition
for Hollywood.
So we can still keep that project.
[in unison] Get the phone!
[telephone ringing]
[in English] Shine Artist Management,
how may I help you?
[Andrea] You can't tell us
what to do.
- I don't care about what they say.
- Yes.
Mind your own talents.
I'll mind my own.
Ms. Andrea?
[clamoring]
[Sofie] Sir Gabriel?
It can't always be about you!
Sir Matthew?
[Andrea] You always find fault
in what we do.
You know, we can grow, too!
[shushes]
[in unison] What?
It's Sir Samuel.
Oh...
Hey, Samuel. Uh...
We're all here!
You miss us already, boss?
[in English] How's everything?
Are you having fun?
[doctor] Sorry,
this is not Samuel Mendiola.
I'm calling from Avalon Clinic
in Germany.
What's this about?
I'm sorry to tell you this.
Mr. Samuel Mendiola suffered
a massive heart attack
late last night.
How is he?
He passed away about an hour ago.
[foreboding music]
Yes, hello.
This is Matthew Buenaventura,
associate of Samuel.
- [electricity crackles]
- [loud thud]
[closing theme music]